

SKILLS

Spoken Languages: English, French (Intermediate)

Programming Languages:

TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby

Frameworks/Libraries and

Environments: NodeJS, React, Ajax, Express, EJS, JQuery, SASS, Ruby on Rails

Systems, CMS and

Databases: Git, SQL, Github,

MongoDB

Testing: Mocha, Chai, Jest,

Cypress, Storybook

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs

Sept. 2020 to Dec. 2020 Diploma Full Stack Web Development

Brock University

Sept. 2015 to Apr. 2019 B.A. Honours Sociology

SUMMARY

My name is Bill Watters, I am a software developer with a deep passion for building innovative products to create positive change in the world. Before becoming a software developer I worked in the caretaking of individuals with special needs and the security industry. This has made me excellent at working under immense pressure while showing compassion, communicating, and keeping calm when faced with challenges. I also have experience working as a full stack developer in a fast-paced and agile startup where I have learned how to become a core contributor to a production-level product. Going forward I want to find my next role that will build on my skills and knowledge of software development.

PROJECTS

Community Soccer

This is a web application where users can create and join soccer matches in their community.

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Reactis

Back-end: PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express

Scheduler Nov. 2020 to Nov. 2020

This is a scheduling application that was built to add, edit, and remove interviews.

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Reactis

Back-end: PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express Testing: Cypress, Jest, Storybook

Food Ordering App

Nov. 2020 to Nov. 2020

Nov. 2020 to Dec. 2020

This is a web application is a takeout and delivery app for a single restaurant.

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Javascript, SASS Back-end: PostgreSQL, Nodejs, Express

Jungle-Rails

Oct. 2020 to Nov. 2020

This is an online shopping website where users can search and buy items posted

by the owner.

Front-end: HTML, CSS Back-end: Ruby on Rails

EMPLOYMENT

Honeybee

Full Stack Developer Intern

Toronto, ON Jan. 2021 to Mar. 2021

Responsible for building new web application features in a fully remote, agile environment using a MERN stack.

- Led the front end development for a referral system which generated a 36% increase in active users.
- Developed a new full stack feature to facilitate the transfer of money on the web application between users.
- Redesigned and optimized the login and authorization systems on the front and back end.

Group Home Support Worker Families 1st

Hamilton, ON Nov. 2019 to Sept. 2020

- Implemented and carried out behavioural support plans for individuals with a variety of challenging needs.
- Fulfilled the daily care and treatment for individuals with a variety of disabilities.
- Responded to the behavioural issues of clients within the home and wrote detailed reports of the incidents.